# **Alison Reilly**

reillyamr@gmail.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/alisonreilly | Github github.com/Tsunamins | Portfolio alisonreilly.dev

Experienced in Fullstack Software Engineering with a background in hospitality. Possess strong skills in critical thinking and need anticipation that help large enterprise companies drive sales and customer experiences.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Typescript
React
Java
Python
Redis
Selenium
Jest
JavaScript

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer I, Parchment (acquired by Instructure), Remote 9/2022 – present

- Built a front end component library with React and Typescript, improving development speed and UI standardization
- Increased reliability and safeguarded future changes by writing unit tests with React testing-library and Jest
- Integrated on an additional team, learning Java and Spring Boot for background services and full stack applications
- Created new API endpoints with Spring Boot, Hibernate and Lombok, modified database with Liquibase

### Software Engineer I, American Express, Remote 12/2021 – 9/2022

- Added front end features for an enterprise automations platform using React and company design library
- Implemented API routes in Golang and Python with Flask, concentrating on value add reporting for leadership
- Integrated a Redis Client speeding up reporting and other endpoint processing times
- Improved automated UI testing coverage by adding Gitlab pipeline Selenium Browser tests

### Technical Support Engineer, ServiceNow, Remote 3/2021 - 12/2021

- Utilized platform debugging tools to identify conflicting security rules and other platform settings
- Employed Chrome Dev Tools, platform tools and other techniques for client side and server side debugging
- Increased ticket resolution speed by coordinating consultations with Customers, team members and developers
- Created knowledge base articles on findings enhancing the available support documentation for users and employees

### Backend Developer Intern, 1909 Coworking, Remote 8/2020 - 03/2020

Internship project building middleware and integrations

- Integrated OfficeRnd & Salesforce REST APIs using NodeJS and Firebase functions
- Routed web hook response of OfficeRnd with ExpressJS ensuring separation of concerns
- Communicated goals with product owner and other 1909 team members on a bi-weekly basis to sync goals

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School 1/2019 - 03/2020

Software Engineering: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux

## LaGuardia Community College, Long Island City, NY 3/2013 - 08/2017

Math and Science classes taken with Calculus, C++, Biology and writing concentrations

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Fauxtel Hotels - https://github.com/Tsunamins/FauxtelHotels | https://youtu.be/G4u KgDfBYI

- P project from Flatiron School Software Engineering program, updated and maintained with latest packages
- Created a mock hotel website with reservation features using React, Redux toolkit, react-day-picker
- Added JWT token-based authentication and authorization, confirmed new accounts with email verification
- Built an API backend using Ruby on Rails for data associations with PostgreSQL database, utilized fast\_isonapi